# Hugo A.Morais

## Front-End Developer

An enthusiast for technologies and processes of creation, with Frontend tools I can have the best of these two aspects. Experienced in the field working with customer solutions, company business rules and web page development. hugones45@gmail.com

(31) 99591-7049

Araxá, Brazil

linkedin.com/in/hugo-alex

github.com/Hugones45



### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# **WebFront Freenlance**

Hugo Alex Dev 04/2022 - Present

Araxá, Brazil

Provide quality services focused on web programming using the JavaScript and React.

#### Tasks

- Form validation and API REST.
- Component creation and maintenance.
- Responsive Web Design.

# **Systems Technical Support**Bit Tech

07/2022 - Present

Araxá, Brazil

Software house focused in the development of technologies for the mass services and insurance market.

#### Tasks

- User support service and investigation of system errors.
- Knowledge of the company's business rules.
- Supervision and maintenance of registrations, campaigns and products.
- Assessments of current platform needs for development of future updates.

#### **CERTIFICATES**

Scrum Training

React: developing with Javascript

React with JavaScript: Dealing with Static Files

React: how components work.

React: developing with TypeScript

## **EDUCATION**

# **Analysis and Systems Development**

Universidade Cruzeiro Do Sul

08/2021 - Present

Araxá, Brazil

#### Courses

- Systems Analysis and Design.
- Web Programming.
- Secure Software Development.
- Application Monitoring.
- Database Systems.

# **SKILLS AND SOFT SKILLS**



### PERSONAL FRONT-END PROJECTS

Development of games with JavaScript.

- Spread sheet made for RPG masters to follow up player's skills updates
- Old Snake Game.
- T-rex running browser game.

#### Development applications with React.

- Personal Expense Manager made with React and TypeScript
- Finance Manager for Projects made with React and JavaScript.
- Puzzle game with the name of native bees of Brazil created for ecological and educational purposes. Made with React.

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

- After three months of work I started to saved money for the company solving maintenance problems in a fast hast.
- Reduce lead times by 80% on my support team.
- Assisted the company in incorporating tools from the React library for future projects.
- Show the importance of local biodiversity through volunteer work with personal web applications.

#### LANGUAGES

#### English

Full Professional Proficiency

#### Portuguese

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

#### Spanish

Limited Working Proficiency

#### INTERESTS

Board games development

Software creation

Sculpture with clay

Work Out